export const INFORMATIONCOMMUNICATIONTECHA2021 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "A report which calls attention to out of the ordinary is referred to as",
A: "adhoc report",
B: "demand report",
C: "exception report",
D: "periodic report",
answer: "C. exception report",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "Buying and offering of services on the web is called",
A: "e-business",
B: "e-mail",
C: "internet buying",
D: "internet sales",
answer: "A. e-business",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "Mixing a primary colour and a secondary colour in a desktop publishing application produces",
A: "shade",
B: "colour triad",
C: "tertiary colour",
D: "split complimentary",
answer: "C. tertiary colour",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "A feature in spreadsheet application that displays only the specified data in columns according to a given criteria is",
A: "Filter",
B: "Formula",
C: "Pivot",
D: "Sort",
answer: "A. Filter",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "Which of the following types of memory is EEPROM?",
A: "Dynamic",
B: "Non-volatile",
C: "Static",
D: "Volatile",
answer: "B. Non-volatile",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "The communication path between a central processor and other devices is called",
A: "Bus",
B: "Cache",
C: "Channel",
D: "Network",
answer: "A. Bus",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "The utility program used in freeing space on the hard disk is called",
A: "Check disk",
B: "Disk cleanup",
C: "Format disk",
D: "Defragmenter",
answer: "B. Disk cleanup",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "The device used within the computer that conducts and draws heat away from the processor is called",
A: "Radiator",
B: "Heat Sink",
C: "Thermostat",
D: "Air conditioner",
answer: "B. Heat Sink",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "The computer keyboard combinations which enables users to start the process of warm booting is",
A: "Ctrl + K",
B: "Shift + F",
C: "Ctrl + Alt + Del.",
D: "Crtl + Shift + Esc",
answer: "C. Ctrl + Alt + Del.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "The term computer program is also referred to as",
A: "Procedure",
B: "Software",
C: "Topology",
D: "Utility",
answer: "B. Software",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "A programming language that is used to write source codes that are independent of a particular type of a computer is called",
A: "Assembly language",
B: "High-level language",
C: "Low-level language",
D: "Machine language",
answer: "B. High-level language",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "The programming language C++ was developed by",
A: "Charles Babbage",
B: "Bill Gate",
C: "David Filo",
D: "Bjarne Strudsteup",
answer: "D. Bjarne Stroustrup",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "Which of the following QBASIC commands is used to assigned values to variables?",
A: "DATA",
B: "INPUT",
C: "LET",
D: "PRINT",
answer: "C. LET",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "Flowchart is a pictorial representation of",
A: "Algorithm",
B: "Charts",
C: "Data types",
D: "Mnemonics",
answer: "A. Algorithm",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "The symbol used to represent branching in a flowchart is",
A: "Circle",
B: "Diamond",
C: "Rectangle",
D: "Triangle",
answer: "B. Diamond",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "A network topology in which the nodes connect to a common medium to form a closed loop is called",
A: "Bus",
B: "Mesh",
C: "Ring",
D: "Star",
answer: "C. Ring",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "The linking of computers with a communication system is called",
A: "Assembling",
B: "Networking",
C: "Pairing",
D: "Routing",
answer: "B. Networking",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "The combination of one or more related characters a user accesses in a database is called",
A: "Field",
B: "File",
C: "Form",
D: "Record",
answer: "A. Field",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "A database program is made up of primary components called",
A: "Commands",
B: "Items",
C: "Objects",
D: "Properties",
answer: "C. Objects",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "Each row of a table in a database is called",
A: "Character",
B: "Field",
C: "Key",
D: "Record",
answer: "D. Record",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "If base 10 is called decimal number system then base 8 is",
A: "Binary number",
B: "Duodecimal number",
C: "Hexadecimal number",
D: "Octal number",
answer: "D. Octal number",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "The real business and competitive value of information technology lies in the",
A: "Software applications that are used by many companies",
B: "Capabilities of the hardware and the speed at which it processes information.",
C: "Infrastructure of hardware, networks and other I.T facilities that are commonly used.",
D: "Capabilities of the software and value of the information a business acquires and uses.",
answer: "D. Capabilities of the software and value of the information a business acquires and uses.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "Which of the following is not a technology driver for an information system?",
A: "Enterprise applications",
B: "Networks and the internet",
C: "Collaborative technologies",
D: "Knowledge asset management",
answer: "D. Knowledge asset management",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "Which of the following terms are related to cybercrimes? \nI. Flamming \nII. Hacking \nIII. Scamming \nIV. Spamming",
A: "I and II only",
B: "II and III only",
C: "III and IV only",
D: "I, II and IV only",
answer: "B. II and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "When a designer raises an item into a higher hierarchy in an outline in a desktop publishing application, the term used is",
A: "Contracting",
B: "Demoting",
C: "Expanding",
D: "Promoting",
answer: "C. Expanding",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "Which of the following formulas will display the current seconds past the minute of the clock in a spreadsheet application?",
A: "=SECOND()",
B: "=SECOND(NOW( ))",
C: "=SECOND(YEAR( ))",
D: "=SECOND(HOUR ( ))",
answer: "B. =SECOND(NOW( ))",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "Which if the following options retain its information when power to the computer system is turned off?",
A: "RAM",
B: "ROM",
C: "DIMM",
D: "DRAM",
answer: "B. ROM",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "Which of the following devices is not used to read and image into a computer?",
A: "Bar code scanner",
B: "Flat bed scanner",
C: "Infrared pointer",
D: "Smart phone",
answer: "C. Infrared pointer",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "Which of the following programs is not an operating system?",
A: "Linus",
B: "Opera",
C: "Unix",
D: "Windows",
answer: "B. Opera",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "The major function of operating system is",
A: "Arrangement of files",
B: "Collection of files",
C: "Resource management",
D: "Organization of the data",
answer: "C. Resource management",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "The following connectors are typically associated with computer mouse except",
A: "PS/2 connector",
B: "Serial comnnector",
C: "Parallel connector",
D: "Bus interface",
answer: "D. Bus interface",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "Missing slot covers on a computer case can cause",
A: "Overheating",
B: "Power surge",
C: "Electromagnetic emission",
D: "Incomplete path for electrostatic discharge",
answer: "A. Overheating",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "A software distributed or downloaded free for use for a limited period of time is referred to as",
A: "Adware",
B: "Freeware",
C: "Shareware",
D: "Trialware",
answer: "C. Shareware",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "Which of the following characters is allowed in a file name?",
A: "?",
B: "*",
C: "–",
D: ":",
answer: "C. –",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "An example of an application software is",
A: "Device driver",
B: "Microsoft Excel",
C: "Ubuntu",
D: "Windows 7",
answer: "B. Microsoft Excel",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "Which of the following QBASIC commands should be used when printing the sum of two integer variables?",
A: "PRINT Z=X+Y",
B: "PRINT “Z=X+Y”",
C: "PRINT X+Y",
D: "PRINT SUM(X,Y)",
answer: "C. PRINT X+Y",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "The HTML tag <table bgcolor= “yellow”> means the",
A: "Border of the cell is yellow",
B: "Border of the table is yellow",
C: "Content of the row is yellow",
D: "Background of the table is yellow",
answer: "D. Background of the table is yellow",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "Which of the following media is a guided communication?",
A: "Coaxial cable",
B: "Microwave",
C: "Radio",
D: "Satelite",
answer: "A. Coaxial cable",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "The computer network topology that uses the least amount of cabling is",
A: "Bus topology",
B: "Mesh topology",
C: "Ring topology",
D: "Star topology",
answer: "A. Bus topology",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "Which of the following addresses is the same as http://127.0.0.1 when typed in the address bar of a web client?",
A: "http://hostip",
B: "http://localhost",
C: "http://local",
D: "http://www.local.com",
answer: "B. http://localhost",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "Figure 1 represents which type of topology?",
A: "Hybrid topology",
B: "Mesh topology",
C: "Ring topology",
D: "Star topology",
answer: "A. Hybrid topology",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "The form which is created by computer program developers in database application is",
A: "Optional to use in place of a report.",
B: "Used to take printout of a form from tables.",
C: "Used for storing special data other than text.",
D: "An input screen for viewing and entering data",
answer: "D. An input screen for viewing and entering data",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "Which of the following data types creates a drop down list of values?",
A: "Memo",
B: "Hyperlink",
C: "OLE Object",
D: "Lookup Wizard",
answer: "D. Lookup Wizard",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "Which of the following options is not a benefit for teachers using information and communications technology (ICT)?",
A: "Creating flexibility",
B: "Sharing of resources",
C: "Gains in technology literacy",
D: "Increase knowledge of children learning.",
answer: "D. Increase knowledge of children learning.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "ICT tools for education does not include",
A: "Blog",
B: "Group class",
C: "Whatsapp group",
D: "Wikis",
answer: "B. Group class",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "The QBASIC codes given below have an error: \nFOR 1=1 TO 12 \nREAD B(1) \nNEXT B \nDATA 1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12 \nSelect the code in the options provided that will correct this error.",
A: "NEXT I",
B: "READ B(I)",
C: "READ B$(I)",
D: "FOR I = 1 TO 12",
answer: "A. NEXT I",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "If 5 is in cell A1, 10 is in cell A2, and 20 is in cell A3, the function to compute the sum of the numbers is",
A: "=A1+A2+A3",
B: "=SUM(A1:A3)",
C: "=SUM(A1:A2:A3:)",
D: "=A1, A2, A3",
answer: "B. =SUM(A1:A3)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "To find product of the numbers 10, 20, 30, 40 and 50 in a spreadsheet, which of the following formulas is correct?",
A: "=PRODUCT(10,20,30,40,50)",
B: "=10x20x30x40x50",
C: "=MULTIPLY (10:50)",
D: "=PRODUCT(10x20x30x40x50)",
answer: "B. =10x20x30x40x50",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "Which of the following formulas represent an absolute cell reference in a spreadsheet application?",
A: "=!A$1",
B: "=$A$1",
C: "=A1",
D: "=$A1",
answer: "B. =$A$1",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "The octal representation of the binary number 1001102 is",
A: "26",
B: "38",
C: "46",
D: "212",
answer: "C. 46",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]